# LALA RUKH

07462550951 • lalarukh.1992@outlook.com

## **Summary:**

As a dedicated software developer specializing in front-end development with a passion for UX/UI design, I consistently deliver top-tier results by following best practices and industry standards. Hard work and determination are my key qualities and I thrive on continuous self-learning. My goal is to blend technical proficiency with creative design to produce inclusive, efficient and delightful user experiences.

# **Work Experience:**

The Access Group, Loughborough (GCSEPod) as Software Developer – Jan 2020 – Present.

- Dedicated 5 years to crafting immersive user experiences while delivering several projects aimed for teachers and students with the help of **React** and **Vue.js** frameworks.
- Mastered Tailwind CSS and Bootstrap to create visually appealing and responsive designs, enhancing user engagement.
- Established and maintained coding standards, ensuring clean and maintainable codebases across projects.
- Increased site performance and reduced site build times significantly by migrating the site from Webpack 4
  to Webpack 5 successfully.
- Leveraged **Figma** to design intuitive user interfaces that elevate user interactions and streamline workflows. Conducted user research and **usability testing** to gather feedback and iterate on **UX** design solutions.
- Developed **AI Co-Pilot** plugins while gaining proficiency with GPT-3 and GPT-4 models, alongside mastering **prompt engineering** techniques.
- Implemented and ensured compliance with WCAG accessibility standards, led accessibility initiatives by implementing and refining rules within existing systems to enhance usability for screen readers.
- Guided junior developers in adapting web development best practices, fostering their growth and skills and a culture of **collaboration** within the team.
- Played a pivotal role in work **planning** meetings, scrums, and consistently ensured on-time **project delivery** throughout my tenure.
- Completed a personal project to get hands-on experience in building and consuming RESTful APIs, utilizing
  Postman for testing and documentation, using Express.js and Node.js for server-side development,
  integrating MongoDB with Mongoose for data management and using React for frontend.

## Hays Travel, Head office Sunderland as Junior Web Developer - Nov 2018 - Jan 2020.

- Played an integral role in delivering the re-development of Hays Cruise website and CMS projects successfully.
- Trained and mentored an intern to proficiently utilize technologies used by the company.
- Developed a new system for the careers team and delivered the essential training successfully.

### Hays Travel, Head Office Sunderland as Graduate Web Developer - Mar 2018 - Nov 2018.

- Received training and mentorship to get up to speed with the existing system and technologies.
- Worked on several projects such as redevelopment of Hays Faraway CMS while learning the new technologies.
- Provided technical support for updating the existing web platforms for the company as per requests from different departments on a day-to-day basis.

## Bede Gaming, Newcastle upon Tyne as Technology Intern - Feb 2018 – Mar 2018.

- Gained an insight into Company operations and gambling platform industry.
- Developed technical and communication skills and applied knowledge practically within the workplace.
- Worked on a JavaScript based project using company's SPINE API for extracting player data.

## **Education:**

#### Northumbria University, Newcastle Upon Tyne, UK – (Distinction)

**Masters** in Computing and IT (*Advanced Practice*) | *January 2018*. Database modelling 90% | OO Analysis and design 74% | Object Oriented Programming 84% | Website development 96% | Overall **80.5%** 

### NFC Institute of Engineering and Fertilizer Research, Faisalabad, Pakistan

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science | *November 2013* | 3.26 GPA | Web Technologies A+|Software Engineering B+| Database Systems B+| Programming Languages A+|OO Analysis and Design B+

## **Technical Skills:**

Vue.js, React.js, Tailwind, Bootstrap, CSS, HTML5, JavaScript, Figma, Git, Postman.

# **Voluntary Experience:**

- 1. Northumbria University, Newcastle upon Tyne as Class Representative. January 2017 December 2017.
- 2. NFC Blood Donor Society, NFC Institute of Engineering and Fertilizer Research, Pakistan as **in-charge Management**. November 2012 September 2013.
- 3. NFC Blood Donor Society, NFC Institute of Engineering and Fertilizer Research, Pakistan as **Computer Science Representative**. November 2011- October 2012.
- 4. NFC Blood Donor Society (BDS), NFC Institute of Engineering and Fertilizer Research, Pakistan as **In-charge Arts and Display Wing**. November 2010 October 2011.
- 5. NFC Association for Computing Machinery (ACM) Society, NFC Institute of Engineering, Pakistan as **Hostel Representative**. February 2012 March 2013.

## **Achievements:**

- The Access Group Hackathon winner for 2023 and 2024.
- IELTS academic Test BAND 7.5

#### **Interests**

- Painting, Squash, Working out.
- Exploring and discovering new places.

Linkedin: www.linkedin.com/in/lala-rukh-9019a6144/

Github: https://github.com/lalarukh1

References are available on request.